Chris Campbell

Denver, CO 80203 | 248-877-0395 | christopherecampbell@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

I am a full stack developer with 13 years of experience in sales and marketing with a focus on leading teams in the e-commerce space. I have an entrepreneurial spirit and started a successful real estate business during the pandemic. As a leader of large customer-facing teams, I spent significant time working with product and engineering as a key stakeholder representing the voice of the customer. Seeing how new products were built to increase customer engagement and sales was always one of my favorite parts of the job. This led me to studying software engineering at General Assembly. I can't wait to join a team that actually builds new products and features when I graduate.

TECHNICAL & INTERPERSONAL SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, EJS

Libraries and Frameworks: React, Express.js, Node.js

Databases and other: MongoDB, RESTful Routing, JSON API, Mongoose, Git, GitHub

Tools: Salesforce.com, Looker, Canva, CRM Systems

Skills: Leadership, Team Building, Change Management, Hiring, Strategic Planning, OKRs, Data Analysis, Collaboration, Problem Solving, Software Development, Frontend Development, Backend Development, Writing

Languages: Fluent in Spanish, conversational in Italian

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

YASSZEE - GitHub | App - JavaScript | HTML | CSS

A Yahtzee-style game that lets users play as their favorite drag queens and handles all scoring rules to automatically declare a winner

- Built scoring logic for all 13 possible hands in a game of Yahtzee that auto-calculate at the end of the game to declare a winner
- Implemented a modal to let users pick their favorite drag queen as their character that dynamically updates the game board with interactive soundbites
- Created a mobile version that dynamically manipulates the DOM based on the current player for better mobile user experience

Butter - GitHub | App - JavaScript | HTML | CSS | EJS | MongoDB | Node.js | Express.js | REST API

Butter is a node.js cookbook application that lets you search, save, import, and copy recipes that you can edit and leave notes on over time. No more guessing on if you used 2 or 3 tablespoons of turmeric in that curry you love. Keeping track of your favorite recipes is as easy as Butter.

- Connected to Edamam's recipe search API, used API response to render recipes and link to original recipe source
- Built a web scraper to allow users to easily import recipe data including images by just entering the url of the recipe
- Deployed full CRUD functionality for multiple data resources stored in MongoDB with Express.js backend
- Implemented authentication via Google OAuth and user authorization preventing users from altering data they don't own

EXPERIENCE

Dream Home Denver, LLC, Owner, Real Estate Broker

Denver. CO. 06/2020 - Present

- Solely responsible for P&L, marketing strategy, and all sales. Currently operating a profitable real estate business
- Provided innovative solutions leading to over \$10MM in closed sales volume to date across 25 transactions
- Broke records for price per square foot on listings at 550 E 12th Ave and 100 Park Ave West
- Designed a cohesive brand identity used across all marketing channels including print, social media, and events
- Recognized as part of the "Best of Zillow" in the Denver Market

1stdibs (Nasdag: DIBS), Sr. Director of Sales

Denver, CO, 07/2019 - 04/2020

- Opened a satellite office in Denver in two months that saved 1stdibs 20% per full time employee total cost
- Hired both individual contributors and managers to build a team of 30 across NYC, Denver, and London offices
- Represented the voice of the customer to achieve go to market fit for 1stdibs Trade offering
- Consistently had some of the highest employee engagement scores both for overall job satisfaction and satisfaction with management in the entire company

Director of Sales

- Grew 1stdibs Trade annual gross merchandise value from \$50MM to \$100MM between 2017 and 2019 by increasing total number of active clients and average spend per client
- Worked cross functionally with marketing, product, and other customer facing teams to launch industry leading trade rewards program
- Introduced consultative sales and wrote documentation for sales process along with training and onboarding
- Created a brand new sales function complete with comp plans and sales process to address a declining number of new customers across our trade and consumer businesses
- Doubled the response rate of emails through sales automation and A/B testing of email strategy
- Partnered with the People Team to create a predictable hiring process and best practices resulting in fast, quality hiring that was adapted to other departments across the company
- Developed 5 reps into highly effective managers across sales, customer experience and sales operations
- Decreased time spent on non-sales activities by 47%

Homepolish, Director of Commercial Sales

New York, NY, 06/2016 - 03/2017

- Implemented Salesforce.com from scratch including vetting implementation partners, creating custom objects, workflows, and dashboards to increase overall visibility into our business and empower revenue generating employees across business units
- Doubled the average gross profit per commercial customer
- Built sales team and process from the ground up with a 65% close rate on identified opportunities
- Developed the company's first ever system for compensation plans and commission structures for Sales Development Rep and Account Executive roles
- Led forecasting and goal setting for 2017 across all business units by analyzing historical sales data for the company to uncover insights

Poppin - Acquired by Kimball Intl (Nasdaq: KBAL), Director of Sales

New York, NY, 05/2015 - 06/2016

- Lead the overall strategy of Poppin's B2B sales org to increase rep efficiency and grow year over year sales by 215%
- Grew sales org to 50 reps across Account Executive, Sales Development Rep, Manager, and specialized Trade Reps
- Built a customer-first sales culture during a period of rapid growth resulting in Poppin consistently having a net promoter score in the 80s

Sales Manager

New York. NY. 12/2013 - 05/2015

• Transitioned our sales organization from a generalized Account Executive team to a team with specialized Account Executive and Sales Development Rep roles which grew our year over year sales by 179%

Account Executive

New York, NY, 06/2011 - 12/2013

• Increased average monthly run rate for a rep from \$5K to \$50K before being promoted to manage the team

EDUCATION

General Assembly

Remote, Certificate Expected: 03/2023

Full-stack software engineering 420+ hour program focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and team collaboration strategies

University of Miami, Bachelor of Science in Communication - Cum Laude Majors: Media Management and Spanish Minor: Business Administration Studied abroad at Universidad de Alicante in Alicante, Spain

Coral Gables, FL 2009